techforluddites.com 2019-09-28

# Legal Stuff | Tech for Luddites

Effective Date: July 14, 2018

### Privacy

Tech for Luddites understand that your privacy is of critical importance. This privacy policy describes what information we collect from you via the Site and how we use and disclose such information.

 **Use of Cookies**

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

Tech for Luddites uses cookies for the following purposes:

  * Personalization: To store information about your preferences and to personalize the website for you
  * Advertising: To help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you
  * Analysis: To help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services

T4L use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to Tech for Luddites is used to create reports about the use of the site. Google’s privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including Tech for Luddites. Some features of the site may cease to be available to you.

 **Interest-Based Advertising**

Tech for Luddites is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the site. AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google, and other advertising partners will track your behavior on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies. You may opt out of the use of Google’s DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/) or by visiting [aboutads.info](http://aboutads.info/).

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

 **Email Addresses**

Tech for Luddites may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter, or enter a promotion. T4L will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us, and may also from time to to send you emails regarding the site or other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you. You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button in the email.

T4L will not share your email address with any third parties.

 **Changes to the Privacy Policy**

Tech for Luddites may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most recent version of the privacy policy will always be posted on the site, with the “Effective Date” posted at the top of the policy. If we make any material changes to our privacy policy or how we handle your personal information, or we are going to use any personal information in a manner that is materially different from that stated in our privacy policy at the time we collected such information, you will be given a reasonable opportunity to consent to the change. If you do not consent, your personal information will be used as agreed to under the terms of the privacy policy in effect at the time we obtained that information. By using the Tech for Luddites website or services after the effective date, you are deemed to consent to our then-current privacy policy. We will use information previously obtained in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect when the information was obtained from you.

### Affiliate Relationships

Tech for Luddites is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

Tech for Luddites is also a participant in other affiliate programs, which means that if you take certain actions (click through, make a purchase) from links on this website, I may receive a commission for the referral. I do not receive any payments or products or services for free or discounted rates as compensation for writing about them and I provide my honest opinion about any products or services I have actually used. I also provide links to products or services I have not used but in those cases I provide no endorsements of them.
